[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b774", "question": "Brigham Young was a leader of which religious group?", "answer": "Mormons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b318", "question": "What famous leader was assassinated on March 15, 44 BC, the Ides of March?", "answer": "Caesar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4f", "question": "What LSU Tiger was drafted by the Orlando Magic in 1992?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d7", "question": "What made-for-TV movie starred Alfre Woodard as Eunice Evers?", "answer": "Miss Evers' Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cab30775fa611bce67fd", "question": "What do the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame and the Louvre have in common?", "answer": "A design by the same architect -- I.M. Pei provided the design for the entrances to both museums.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe771a2eec85e375820b2fb", "question": "What does a flower worn behind a woman's right ear mean in Hawaii?", "answer": "She's single", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946c", "question": "What actor voiced Doc Hudson in the 2006 movie \"Cars\"?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7eb1bb24f84e0b9f9ffdb", "question": "What fell into the pool in the film \"Caddyshack\" which caused a major exodus?", "answer": "A Baby Ruth candy bar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6638ea5bfecdd737e0851", "question": "Who was the youngest Chief Justice appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "John Jay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ed", "question": "What member of Fleetwood Mac released a 1981 solo hit single titled \"Trouble\"?", "answer": "Lindsey Buckingham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a155", "question": "Who married actress Julia Roberts in 1993?", "answer": "Lyle Lovett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bf", "question": "What does Marilyn Monroe say are a \"girl's best friend\" in Gentlemen Prefer Blondes?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cb41877e98cb97778a17", "question": "The ancient Phoenician city of Constantine is located in what modern-day Arab country?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d07772870e6f05ba600864", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea3", "question": "What youngest brother of the music world was a former host of \"Solid Gold\"?", "answer": "Andy Gibb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9437574a5ce6b56b8245", "question": "What job did Agatha Christie's second husband do?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e75", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"A Patch of Blue\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Hartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d46f9af8e329de4f877888", "question": "Liza Minelli played what character in the 1972 film \"Cabaret\"?", "answer": "Sally Bowles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f4", "question": "Who\u2019s Fred Flintstone\u2019s best friend?", "answer": "Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a12", "question": "What was the name of the man cub in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Mowgli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b32", "question": "Peter Wolf was the lead singer and frontman of what band during the 1970's and early 1980's?", "answer": "J. Geils Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea5", "question": "What takes its name from the Japanese for \"whimsical pictures\"?", "answer": "Manga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338988", "question": "What subject does Miss Sherman teach in the musical \"Fame\"?", "answer": "English", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a24", "question": "Who aimed his \"Emporio\" clothing line at younger buyers?", "answer": "Giorgio Armani", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe6", "question": "What country borders Guatemala to the north?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7a", "question": "What word describes a cut of steak containing both the T-\u00adbone and the tenderloin?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1e", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 14th July?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a507", "question": "What three countries share the island of Borneo?", "answer": "Indonesia, Malaysia and Brunei", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ac", "question": "Gastritis affects which body organ?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb4", "question": "What was first presented at Hollywood\u2019s Roosevelt Hotel on May 16, 1929?", "answer": "The Academy Awards (Oscars)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65e5b1f3c0ead6880d62a", "question": "In the 12th chapter of the \"Book of Revelation\", which angel leads a battle against a dragon?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54e", "question": "What digit does not exist in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ef", "question": "Who played Daniel LaRusso in the 1984 film \"The Karate Kid\"?", "answer": "Ralph Macchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff515beff04d658268c92ec", "question": "What queen led a famous revolt against the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Zenobia, queen of the Palmyrene Empire, expanded the empire, by conquering Egypt and expelling the Roman prefect, Tenagino Probus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8d4ec2b42d4a3561a9efd", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Darcy Parker\u2019s alias?", "answer": "Darcia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cc26bb53d1af658864de", "question": "Which singer sang \"I Believe in Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "Greg Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac85", "question": "What was banned in Mississippi in 1907 that didn't become legal there again until 1966?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e0", "question": "\"Mork & Mindy\" was a spin-off of what TV show?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffc091cf6db9ac4808cfb", "question": "Which country is home to the language with the world's shortest alphabet?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960c", "question": "What pastime does Jeff \"The Dude\" Lebowski enjoy?", "answer": "Bowling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca7", "question": "What musical talent does the Devil display in the song \"The Devil Went Down to Georgia\"?", "answer": "Fiddle playing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14b", "question": "Who is the youngest member of the band Boyzone?", "answer": "Ronan Keating", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a6", "question": "What US city is services by McCarran International Airport?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a71", "question": "What is the name of the milkman in \"Fiddler on the Roof\"?", "answer": "Tevye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"glitch\"?", "answer": "Yiddish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed8", "question": "What other singer's death inspired Paul Simon to write \"The Late Great Johnny Ace\"?", "answer": "John Lennon's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abea", "question": "Easter Island is a part of which South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c469", "question": "What perfume ingredient comes from the intestine of the sperm whale?", "answer": "Ambergris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb29d5c9bff04efae6d75a", "question": "Who wrote the novels \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15d", "question": "Mother Teresa was awarded the 1979 Nobel Prize for what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3231a6bf195a31e15d7386", "question": "Who shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize with Menachem Begin?", "answer": "Mohamed Anwar Al-Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f5c501dd7bf43be5e82b", "question": "What variety of bananas is the most commonly sold in stores?", "answer": "Cavendish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad79", "question": "What ships did Vikings sail in?", "answer": "Longboats", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067dc4ff9c0647b50a8074", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15f", "question": "Fax is short for which word?", "answer": "Facsimile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd5aa7e83c707845b2164", "question": "What was the name of the whale in the 1993 movie, \"Free Willy\"?", "answer": "Keiko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c491", "question": "What astronomical aid takes its name from Greek words meaning \"far seeing\"?", "answer": "Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96e2b23c87fd04dd15e34", "question": "What is the oldest sport in history?", "answer": "Wrestling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b49c", "question": "Which country was selected as a host of the 1916 Olympic Games, but didn't actually host them?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b3bdfb6c85e9e634ff43", "question": "In architecture, what is the structure that forms the arms of a cross-shaped church named?", "answer": "Transept", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a785", "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b5", "question": "What did A.J. stand for on the TV show \"Simon & Simon\"?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a6", "question": "Who produced the radio show \"The War of the Worlds\"?", "answer": "Orson Welles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5b", "question": "Which terrorist group invaded the Munich Olympic Village in 1972?", "answer": "Black September", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e147ef76ca6dac04a20ca52", "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30e", "question": "Which character did Evan Handler play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Charlie Runkle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a48", "question": "Who was awarded the very first Grammy award for best R&B performance?", "answer": "Buddy Bruce", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c279", "question": "What is December's birthstone?", "answer": "Turquoise", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51cb8ff04d658268c931a", "question": "Pilgrims never called themselves Pilgrims, what were they?", "answer": "Separatists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923c", "question": "What street do the women of \"Desperate Housewives\" live on?", "answer": "Wisteria Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9b02596a59cbdfbd3c9", "question": "What was the first crime Billy the Kid was arrested for?", "answer": "Stealing clothes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339962", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what nickname did Milhouse give himself?", "answer": "Thrillhouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ed", "question": "In The Simpsons, who once attacked Lisa when she was cross-country skiing?", "answer": "Vicious deer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af47", "question": "Who was the fourth president of the United States?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f86a01dd7bf43be5e842", "question": "Where were U.S. coins with an \"O\" on them minted?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b01", "question": "Which character killed Lennie Small?", "answer": "George Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f60", "question": "What supermodel plays the bride in Guns N' Roses' \"November Rain\" video?", "answer": "Stephanie Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe7", "question": "How many players are in a Polo team?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a238", "question": "What studio album did the band Men at Work release in 1981?", "answer": "Business as Usual", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf19", "question": "An onomastician studies what?", "answer": "Names", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010ca6f0775fa611bce67f8", "question": "The \"Malleus Maleficarum\" was a 15th-century guide to dealing with what?", "answer": "Witches -- Witch hunts spread across 15th century Europe, and hunters were guided by many books, including \"Malleus Maleficarum\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb56", "question": "What brand of whisky was created in 1939 Queen of England's visit to Canada?", "answer": "Crown Royal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c804", "question": "What has two poles as a result of Amperian currents?", "answer": "A magnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea3", "question": "What was the nationality of the first man to conquer the summit of mount Everest?", "answer": "New Zealander", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62b", "question": "What is the brightest star in the night sky?", "answer": "Sirius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7b", "question": "Who has been called the first victim of the \"Madden curse\" due to his abrupt 1999 retirement?", "answer": "Barry Sanders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c345", "question": "What metal is also known as quicksilver?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fb", "question": "Who wrote the 1994 novel \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "Frederick Forsyth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c5", "question": "The term \"black market\" was first used during which war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb12b65ff7d326b622a67", "question": "What chemical is denoted by Cm?", "answer": "Curium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c709", "question": "Retinol is another name for what Vitamin?", "answer": "A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43c", "question": "What plastic often has its name shortened to PS?", "answer": "Polystyrene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f60b01dd7bf43be5e82e", "question": "What are Lay's potato chips known as in the U.K.?", "answer": "Walker's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af96b72eedf883a8c708", "question": "Who recorded the song \"I Can't Explain\" in 1964?", "answer": "The Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0aa", "question": "Who won an oscar for her role in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25737b63e5727cf5a4842", "question": "What decade saw the rapid growth in 3D puzzle popularity, largely driven by the Puzz 3D brand?", "answer": "1990s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ebe308d98002fdd633b4", "question": "What is the study of human behaviour and mind called?", "answer": "Psychology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a819", "question": "What river divides the city of Budapest into the \"districts\" of Buda and Pest?", "answer": "The Danube", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6b", "question": "How many individual little squares are there on a standard Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "54", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988e", "question": "In the 1964 stop-motion TV special \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\", who is Rudolph's father?", "answer": "Donner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac4", "question": "What early rock pioneer once told an unresponsive audience, \"I hope you all get heart attacks\"?", "answer": "Jerry Lee Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6d", "question": "Who directed the 1983 sequel to the movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a221", "question": "Who played Beau Geste in the 1939 film by the same name?", "answer": "Gary Cooper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dd70e748bb36357acde1", "question": "In the movie \"National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation\", what does Aunt Bethany recite when asked to say grace?", "answer": "The Pledge of Allegiance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008e05cf4f3bc4a292f8631", "question": "What artist said, \"Every child is an artist\"?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso (The full quote reads,\u00a0\"Every child is an artist, the problem is staying an artist when you grow up.\")", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5922038aa4edfd43a087ade3", "question": "What shapes are used in a Venn diagram?", "answer": "Circles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69e6620565ad31a57c783", "question": "Benito Mussolini died by what method?", "answer": "He was shot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdc", "question": "Lenny Kravtiz is the son of what popular sitcom actress?", "answer": "Roxie Roker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b4274fda37788a9a1dc7", "question": "John Simon Ritchie became famous as who?", "answer": "Sid Vicious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31c", "question": "What does Afforestation mean?", "answer": "Planting of Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe908d901dd7bf43be5e888", "question": "What kind of scientist was Linus Pauling?", "answer": "Chemist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f50", "question": "Who blinded himself with Jocasta's brooch?", "answer": "Oedipus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00c", "question": "What two Orlando Magic teammates made their screen debuts in \"Blue Chips\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal and Anfernee Hardaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbcd", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5954e8208e82ccaf3b9a67bb", "question": "Whose self-titled debut solo album spent the first of three weeks at #1 on Billboard\u2018s Country album chart?", "answer": "Wynonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed6", "question": "The Titanic picked up passengers in which\u00a0two\u00a0ports other than Southampton?", "answer": "Cherbourg and Queenstown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b1744c9bb2d29f81593b6fd", "question": "What year was James Cameron's film \"Aliens\" released?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66c32a5bfecdd737e0890", "question": "What was the first martial art to use colored belts to signify rank?", "answer": "Judo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ca", "question": "Who sang the 1956 song \"Ape Call\"?", "answer": "Nervous Norvus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a9", "question": "Myopia is also known by what other name?", "answer": "Nearsightedness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b631", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"A\" referred to as?", "answer": "Alpha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8bb", "question": "What is the more common name for Clavicle?", "answer": "Collarbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12e", "question": "When did Richard Burton finish his last film?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c904", "question": "What is Infantile Paralysis more commonly known as?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e7", "question": "What is a spinnaker on a boat?", "answer": "Type of sail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba89", "question": "In what year did the NBA introduce the 24 \u00adsecond shot clock?", "answer": "1954", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde4", "question": "Where is the Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Springfield, Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd54fec223966ae8f88cf", "question": "What TV show won the most Emmys in 2018?", "answer": "The Marvelous Mrs. Maisel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca93", "question": "What is the study of the atmosphere called?", "answer": "Meteorology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45d", "question": "What treaty ended the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Treaty of Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59c1ceb47bd84c0ea43ad43a", "question": "Who is Thomas John Woodward better known as?", "answer": "Tom Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfc6d9616e6c6d4eba4f1", "question": "Betsy Ross was born with a fully formed set of what?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe255f4658e585fda9cfa35", "question": "What fast food chain uses the slogan \"We Have The Meats\"?", "answer": "Arby's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef65626ce05a3942286e6c", "question": "Who was the first man to appear on the cover of \"Vogue\"?", "answer": "Richard Gere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce4", "question": "Which \"Friends\" character is the answer to the trivia question in the SNL \"Lazy Sunday\" sketch?", "answer": "Matthew Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbae", "question": "What term for a Bigfoot creature comes from the Salish Indian word meaning \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37a", "question": "What is the five-letter name for a young dog?", "answer": "Whelp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339318", "question": "What dance did Chunk had to perform to gain access to Mikey's house in the 1985 movie \"The Goonies\"?", "answer": "The Truffle Shuffle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d4", "question": "What is the better-known name of the card game \"Twenty-One\"?", "answer": "Blackjack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a214", "question": "What year did audiences first see the character of Betty Boop?", "answer": "1930", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b304", "question": "What title was given to Nanak, the founder of Sikhism?", "answer": "Guru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6aa5f20565ad31a57c817", "question": "Who was the mayor of Chicago from 1955 to 1976?", "answer": "Richard J. Daley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b21", "question": "Stings first solo album was entitled \"The Dream of the Blue...\" what?", "answer": "Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec247b8dc25ca9e12ef638", "question": "Cinnabar is the most common source for which compound?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb00665ff7d326b622a5f", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef929b6ce05a3942286e85", "question": "When did \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\" first air on TV?", "answer": "1964", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe0", "question": "What is the fear of fur called?", "answer": "Doraphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abd196490a8cc1a6e529d", "question": "In The Maze Runner, the \"killzone\" refers to what?", "answer": "The Brain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c18c", "question": "Which UK Label is associated with a dog named Nipper?", "answer": "HMV", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd8", "question": "Who was shot by Jack Ruby?", "answer": "Lee Harvey Oswald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec23668dc25ca9e12ef630", "question": "In what sport is the ball 40 millimetres in diameter and weighs 2.7 grams?", "answer": "Table Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea7", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Chip, Dot, Ditto and Trixie?", "answer": "Hi and Lois", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc0f8ec223966ae8f8862", "question": "Why were the Boston Red Sox said to be \"cursed\" between 1918 and 2004?", "answer": "For trading Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ab", "question": "What kind of a head does a Hieracosphinx possess?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da1", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Hagen?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae864587f28483af1e7fdce", "question": "How many countries share common borders with India?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ec7227f57c9fcac0ce71976", "question": "What is the longest running sporting event in the United States?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c1b469bb8041d07a04d", "question": "\"Open Your Hand And Smile\" has been which product's ad slogan?", "answer": "M&M\"s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590720f53745b36be73039f4", "question": "Who played the role of Kris Kringle in the 1994 film \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "Richard Attenborough", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c6", "question": "What word describes the dominance of one state over a group of other states?", "answer": "Hegemony", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96d9e23c87fd04dd15e2c", "question": "Which official is third in the line of the US presidential succession?", "answer": "President Tempore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12f35e39efa6330e0fed7", "question": "Where is the world's shortest commercial runway?", "answer": "Saba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c5", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Manitoba?", "answer": "Winnipeg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5f", "question": "On what thoroughfare does the Muffin Man live?", "answer": "Drury Lane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5b226ce05a3942286e12", "question": "What kind of animal is \"Knuckles,\" the companion of Sonic the Hedgehog?", "answer": "Knuckles is an echidna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b4", "question": "What baseball team signed a contract with Michael Jordan in 1994?", "answer": "Chicago White Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59068002ff9c0647b50a8089", "question": "What motoring show premiered on Amazon Video on November 18, 2016?", "answer": "The Grand Tour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339609", "question": "What was Tom Cruise's call sign in the 1986 movie \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acba", "question": "What was the original Dutch name of New York City?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f2a35cb9e8bda6821362", "question": "What year did \"Petra\" become a UNESCO World Heritage Site?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ade", "question": "In 1996, what action star was named a \"sacred vessel\" of Tibetan Buddhism?", "answer": "Steven Seagal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8cb", "question": "In the world of sports, what does the abbreviation NCAA stand for?", "answer": "National Collegiate Athletic Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0d", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Quickening\"?", "answer": "Highlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339662", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty's monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba39", "question": "Which US first lady founded a center for the treatment of addictions?", "answer": "Betty Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338878", "question": "What color is Nancy Drew's hair?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95aea455722f97b22684d5", "question": "Which Star Wars character is the first to be partially named after director George Lucas\u2019 son?", "answer": "Dexter Jettster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b1", "question": "In \"Bart vs. Australia,\" Homer threatened the members of Parliament with what?", "answer": "A big boot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab90", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbae5750738315b1fb74e22", "question": "Who was the first football player drafted in 1936 during the first ever NFL draft?", "answer": "Jay Berwanger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b583e662d71a53650ffb", "question": "In which classic children's book does the protagonist only eat cabbage?", "answer": "\"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9db", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa0", "question": "What is typically considered to be the earliest, mass produced brand of hot sauce?", "answer": "Tabasco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a978", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Riksdag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3d", "question": "How many players are there in a standard quidditch team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff5", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Paris' wife before he was smitten by Helen?", "answer": "Oenone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede4396ce05a3942286dda", "question": "Which famous drummer was nicknamed \"The Beast\" while intoxicated?", "answer": "John Bonham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43d", "question": "What was George Hepplewhite's profession?", "answer": "Furniture maker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e57bfe83fe1f2a824bbf", "question": "Who invented the bidet?", "answer": "Christophe Des Rosiers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14679b0ee8c595b6d39c0", "question": "What classic book inspired the name of Starbucks?", "answer": "Moby Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd96a9523c87fd04dd15e13", "question": "Larry Page and Sergey Brin founded what company in Menlo Park?", "answer": "Google, Inc.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13b", "question": "What frontiersman led the party that cut the Wilderness Road through the Cumberland Gap?", "answer": "Daniel Boone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c4e3877e98cb977789a9", "question": "Where can you find the Cathedral of St. Basil the Blessed?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f57", "question": "The red Oslo sky in what 1893 painting has been explained as a result of the eruption of Krakatoa?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b5", "question": "In 1892, 15-year-old Alonzo \"Lonnie\" Clayton became the youngest winner of which sporting event?", "answer": "The Kentucky Derby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db78a20ab2c8f322317ff5", "question": "John Downland was an English Renaissance composer for which instrument?", "answer": "The Lute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a118", "question": "On the 80's album \"Purple Rain\", who backed Prince?", "answer": "The Revolution", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ea57b24f84e0b9f9ffd3", "question": "What is the fear of worms, especially parasitic ones, known as?", "answer": "Scoleciphobia, helminthophobia or vermiphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea49feff048f679a45abbf", "question": "When blood becomes more acid than normal, what it is the condition called?", "answer": "Acidosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6679c52a821ff76ae8afe", "question": "Which historical member of British royalty made Christmas trees mainstream there?", "answer": "Prince Albert, the German husband of Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a267", "question": "What year did The Trammps release the song \"Disco Inferno\"?", "answer": "1976", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae2", "question": "A \"Tiercel\" is the traditional term for a male what?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bbd2d96d05b23b28164f", "question": "What event prompted the first New Year\u2019s Eve ball drop in Times Square?", "answer": "New York Times paper owner Adolph Ochs hired a metal worker to build the ball-drop due to a fireworks ban in the city.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1c", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Parkes?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964b", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1995 movie \"Babe\"?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c617", "question": "How many chromosomes are in human DNA?", "answer": "46", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78a", "question": "What is the only Canadian Province which borders the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "British Columbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c7", "question": "What year did Suriname gain its independence from the Kingdom of the Netherlands?", "answer": "1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6d", "question": "Who painted \"Irises\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339505", "question": "Iron Man's suit is powered by a reactor located where?", "answer": "In his chest", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b4", "question": "What type of bird is the Brown Thrasher?", "answer": "Songbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb6", "question": "What character did actor George Lindsey play on \"The Andy Griffith Show\"?", "answer": "Goober Pyle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b980", "question": "The Acol system is used in which card game?", "answer": "Bridge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e48", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Naked Gun\"?", "answer": "O. J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd174ec223966ae8f88bf", "question": "In \"Finding Nemo\", where is the dentist's diploma from?", "answer": "Pixar University", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f6", "question": "St. Croix, St. John and St. Thomas are part of what US territory?", "answer": "Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ba", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Julie\", what is Romeo's surname?", "answer": "Montague", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14040b0ee8c595b6d3998", "question": "What melting food provided the inspiration for Dali's melting clocks?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6e", "question": "What pair of Disney rodents made their debut in the 1943 cartoon \"Private Pluto\"?", "answer": "Chip 'n' Dale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3d", "question": "What is a Texas Ruby Red?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08a71cf631c2414a13b60", "question": "What is singer Fergie\u2019s real name?", "answer": "Stacy Ann Ferguson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedde376ce05a3942286dac", "question": "Who was originally supposed to direct the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab55", "question": "What is the second largest country in South America?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a1ea20565ad31a57c7a9", "question": "Which US president had a mockingbird he carried on his shoulder?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b173", "question": "What year was construction of the Sistine Chapel completed in?", "answer": "1481", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990af23b72eedf883a8c704", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata in B flat minor\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f85", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for the first screen appearance of Mary Poppins?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c2", "question": "What is the highest peak in the Appalachian range?", "answer": "Mount Mitchell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab0", "question": "Limnology is the study of what?", "answer": "Inland waters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95af9f55722f97b22684d9", "question": "In the \"Harry Potter\" universe, what does the \"Imperius\" Curse do?", "answer": "Controls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c845", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the sclera?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9be", "question": "What is another word for a bird watcher?", "answer": "Twitcher", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7b", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The African Queen\" set?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e8a8b02404ad935a7e1a644", "question": "What is the BTS Variety Show called on their V-LIVE channel?", "answer": "Run BTS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f30", "question": "What literary locale is called \"Manor Farm\" at the start of the novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600a26b3e958e8c9f3127312", "question": "Which New England state produces the majority of the country\u2019s lobsters?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab7", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Greece?", "answer": "Little owl", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbb", "question": "Whose 1939 nomination for the Nobel Peace Prize was retracted in February of that same year?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c95d", "question": "The lumbar spine consists of how many vertebrae?", "answer": "Five", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906f", "question": "What US state are a large portion of Stephen King's novels based in?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61b", "question": "The \"de Havilland Comet IV\" was what?", "answer": "A jet plane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a2da6c0f9723ab15cb47", "question": "Who was the first president to receive full-time Secret Service protection?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cd61bb53d1af658864e8", "question": "How old was Kevin in the 1990 film \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "8 years old", "category": "entertainment"}]